[Music]
Hi, welcome to business center launch
edition 2025 release wave 2. Today we
will speak about uh new functionality in
sustainability value chain. So this is
something what we extended. We started
with value chain previous release but
now we have value chain in a project. So
we will show you all this in details. My
name is Alexander Toto, a product
manager and I have my colleague with me
today.
>> Hi everyone, my name is Jacob Bang. I am
also a product manager working with
Toitch.
Thank you. So what is about earlier in
the first in the beginning we had
sustainability journal general journal
you we could create sustainability
ledger entries. Then we extended this
with the purchase invoices create memos.
So everything was about emission
reporting for environmental impact. But
then we extended it. We enabled this
value chain automation for carbon
footprint embedded. So this is something
what we already introduced in previous
wave. This is much more for brand
reputation, for tracking inside the
company. So in the beginning we had for
uh purchase invoices, for transfer
orders, assembly orders, production
orders, of course sales invoices as
well. But now we extended with the
projects. You can take these with a
project journal and a purchase invoice.
By purchase invoice if you using
purchase uh project number. So what are
business values with this functionality
will really cover end to end scope three
coverage. So we will not be focused only
on supply chain but on projects as well.
So it will be available. We will have
flexible emission projects. It will
definitely improve and streamline your
compliance reporting with the busy
central.
How does it work? It is important to
remember it doesn't work with all gases
only with the carbon equivalent. So even
if you're using different gases
emissions system will calculate these to
carbon equivalent and use only this
information in a value chain. So you can
post emissions using project journal or
purchase invoice. When you post purchase
invoice for project you know you will
get two lines. One will be purchase
another will be negative adjustment
entry. CC will use negative adjustment
entry to enter into sustainability value
entry.
It will be once when you uh finish where
information will be exposed on a project
statistic. So you can run project
statistic and you can find in a task
lines to enable you need to open
sustainability setup to find procurement
uh procurement fast tab and to enable uh
tracking into uh value chain. So that's
it. You just enable this uh one field
and everything will be automatically
enabled. So you just need to enter
information. So now Jacob, you will show
how it look like in a demo. Thank you.
So um let's show quickly how the value
chain uh in projects actually works.
We'll start with uh the sustainability
setup.
And what you'll need to do here is go to
procurement. And for this example, we'll
just enable all the capabilities.
Take a second.
And let's go to items.
And here we'll find the well-known demo
data for the Athens desk. And now we'll
have the sustainability fastub available
to us. You can see it here on the
screen.
We'll set in a standard account number.
We'll add a default number for our CO2
emissions
and we'll calculate the total CO2.
Now let's go to resources.
Here we have Katherine
and she now also has the sustainability
hub. We'll add the account.
We'll set a default number for her as
well and calculate the total CO2.
Now let's look at the project. Go to
project journals.
We will do a test.
This is the posting.
We'll set a number of hours for
Katherine.
And here we'll find the item. And this
is
for the Athens desk.
And similar to before, we will put in a
number here
for two pieces.
After that, we post it.
Just take a second.
Now we have them posted.
So, we'll go to projects.
Here's our project.
And if we scroll over here, we'll see
that we have a number of posts
associated here. This is the test that
we just did. We can dive into the
different attributes in the line items.
And if we go back here, we can actually
look
at the project.
and the statistics.
And this will basically show the
calculations of everything that's been
done as it relates to the workflow.
That was it. Yeah. Thank you, Jakob.
Before we close this session, uh I would
like to remind you to all these links to
find important and interesting
information about Business Central. You
can use them. Do not forget subscribe on
our LinkedIn channel to find all weekly
news the other announcements about
Business Central and watch other videos
not only this one because in this
release we have many of sustainability
interesting functionality not only
sustainability other features as well
for this um edition from previous
edition. So remember AKMSBC YouTube.
Thank you for watching this video.